Guide to the University of Chicago Alumni Foundation Records 1941-1965
University of Chicago Library
University of Chicago. Alumni Foundation. Records
1941-1965
10.75 linear feet (10 boxes)
Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center University of Chicago Library 1100 East 57th Street Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.
The Alumni Foundation was established in 1941 by University of Chicago alumni dedicated to raising money for undergraduate education. This collection tracks fundraising campaigns from 1941 to 1965, and contains correspondence, membership lists, minutes, progress reports, and scrapbooks. It includes the Foundation's "Honor Roll" of donors for 1942-1946.
Information on Use
Access
The collection is open for research.
Historical Note
The Alumni Foundation was established in 1941 by University of Chicago alumni dedicated to raising money for undergraduate education.
Scope Note
This collection tracks fundraising campaigns from 1941 to 1965. The collection is organized first by campaign year, covering fundraising campaigns from 1948-1955 and 1959-1961, each year containing correspondence, membership lists, minutes, and progress reports. The collection includes the Foundation's "Honor Roll" of donors for 1942-1946. Contributions are broken down by graduating class, city, and degree granted; individual contribution amounts are not listed. The collection concludes with scrapbooks containing fundraising materials - predominately mailings - from 1941 to 1965.
Related Resources
The following related resources are located in the Department of Special Collections:
Browse finding aids by topic.
Nuveen, John. Papers
Swift, Harold. Papers
University of Chicago. Development Campaigns and Anniversaries. Records
University of Chicago. Office of the Vice-President. Records
Subject Headings
University of Chicago -- Alumni; University of Chicago. Alumni Foundation
INVENTORY
- Campaign records, 1948-1955 (Box 1, Folder 1-6)
- Campaign records, 1959-1961 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Honor Roll contributions, 1942-1946 (Box 2, Folder 2-6)
- Scrapbook - Alumni Foundation mailings, announcements, newsletters, invitations, brochures, booklets, and accompanying data sheets for 50th Anniversary Fund, 1941 (Box 3)
- Scrapbook - Alumni Association mailings, course information, department and school newsletters, 1942-1944 (Box 4)
- Scrapbook - Alumni Association fundraising materials, 1944 (Box 4)
- Scrapbook - Alumni Foundation fund drive/recruitment mailings and reports, 1942-1947 (Box 5)
- Scrapbook - Alumni Association/UChicago Magazine mailings, promotional materials, expiration and renewal records, 1950-1957 (Box 6)
- Scrapbook - Alumni Association and Foundation mailings, instructions, memos, form letters, 1954-1955 (Box 7)
- Scrapbook - Alumni Foundation fund drive/recruitment mailings, reports, postcards, clippings with annotations, 1958-1959 (Box 7)
- Scrapbook - Alumni Foundation fund drive/recruitment mailings, reports, postcards, clippings, with annotations, 1961-1962 (Box 8)
- Scrapbook - Alumni Foundation fund drive/recruitment mailings, reports, postcards, clippings, with annotations, 1962-1963 (Box 9)
- Scrapbook - Alumni Foundation fund drive/recruitment mailings, reports, postcards, clippings, with annotations, 1964-1965 (Box 10)